a fourth picture with the
sunglasses.
[Music]
The thing is, the people of you in the
Staircase House,
Bonka Rimp
wrote the greatest Lamrim, and Tang
Rimp, his student in the
middle, did all the work.
He was, so to speak, Rosa and
Anatol, and he spent many years of his
life
printing, binding, and so on, his teacher's teachings.  And he
wrote the best commentary on Father Yogeni, and
I have
never published that translation.  So,
all these Diamond Way
translations were supposed to be published, and they weren't actually meant to
be published; they were meant to be given from teacher to student.
But there are
about 20,000
pages of them, and I worked on them for 10 years.
I can say that his
book is truly the
greatest, and we will
study it,
learn from it, and you should know this when
people ask you about your
lineage.
And one more thing before
we
move on to the angels.  The poor angel
always gets the
short end of the stick.  In my
Seram monastery there are 12 magnificent houses.  You
now have five.  There are 12 of them there,
and they've been there for over 500
years.  And my teacher is from the Gerum
House.
In Princeton there was a custom where
the houses were, uh, connected with the
states.  So,
for example, all the students from
Arizona were in one house and did
stupid things together, but it was
fun and we were very
close, we were very familiar with each other. With people
from
other
states, it's a bit more
difficult to make friends,
for example,
New York
people. And
if you have a house for people from your
own state, then that's definitely
better.
And in the past, people
came from far and wide to
study in Gerung's house.  This
is the area of ​​present-day Chengdu.  They
have their own dialect, their
own
language,
but other people can go there too.
Even if you're from Arizona and you're
the
first white person there.
In 600 years, of course there won't be an
Arizona House, and that's why
they said, you can also go
there, you can go to the
[music]
Gerung House, because my teacher was also in
that house, and I just want to briefly explain
why that's the best place,
and that's because
Pain comes from our house.
So, my teacher and
P are coming out of the
house.  It doesn't matter
which house you're in right
now.
Then you can still
say [music], you are still connected to
the Gerungus.  If I ask someone afterwards
, you also say that it's
simply
Pabonari Rimp's story and
he was reborn
and then did his
thing and died and, um, was
then reborn and the boy
from Bonaren Fity was reborn.  Um,
I met him and
I was present at his exams
and was the first
examiner. And at the beginning of the Diamond Way,
when it comes to preparing
for the
Diamond Way, you first have to
learn the teachers.
And it doesn't matter at all which
country they came from.  I
am not exactly
loyal or particularly
connected to Tibetan culture.   There
's
nothing about that that
particularly
attracts me right now.
The singing is
like Bakingop's and it sounds
really terrible,
and I'm
probably the least
American American there is
.  That is to say, I don't feel
particularly connected to any
culture and I don't want to sell you on Tibet
or China right now.  I just have the
feeling, I rather have the feeling, that we
are all one country.
I don't want to
make you Tibetan or sell you something
Chinese
,
but it's
about the way you
live your life.  And in every
country there are people who
follow that, who are on the same path
.
And in all countries, all the people
who are on this path are
in the same country or are
together.  So, you don't have to
wear a funny hat.  Ask me how many times I've
worn this hat here in Rimrock
.  Not even that, because it's simply
not
appropriate.  I once wore my robes in
New York
and this guy stopped me and
said, "Are you a
goddamn Moses?"
Well, I don't think it's that
important what you wear or whether you
carry your bell around with you.  That's
not so
important.  You should dress in a way that
suits your target audience, i.e.,
the people you teach.
So, if
you're in a business environment, in
business life, then you wear a
suit or a nice
dress, and if you're in Diamond Mountain
, then you just wear your
normal clothes.  This is
laminate.  So I'm not selling
anything cultural here, but rather a way of
thinking.  The Diamond Way is a way of
thinking.
So far in this text, we have been bowing to
the
teachers, and that is
someone who performs a prostration.
Our
company simply exploded and our
revenue
doubled a few years quite by chance of
course, and I was desperately
looking for
employees who could work in the gemstone
business.
Because I worked every night until 2 a.m.,
and then I hired this woman
from Barbados
.  She is very
tall
and she
said, "I know someone there," and two
people came.  One of them was
warm.  She wasn't an
actress back then, and I had
a
job interview with her and I
asked, "Tell me, do you really want to
be a secretary here in the diamond business?"  And she
said, no, actually I'd
rather be an actress
.  And then
two months later she
got her first big role and, uh,
I think she was on the
Vog cover more often than any other woman, and
her father still thanks me today for
not hiring her.  And then this
little
woman from Barbados came along, who had a bit of
experience in the gemstone business,
and I said, well, one thing
I have to say, our company
is really
hard here, if
I tell you, you have to work,
sometimes until 1 o'clock, and she
said, I'm
not doing that.
I said, you know, I really, really have a
lot to do
here.
And the woman simply says: "No,
I wo
n't do that."  She said I need
a job, but I'm not going to do it.
As I said, I simply work
when I feel like
working.  And I looked at her
and
thought, then suddenly that word came out of
my mouth and then I
thought, what?
But I hired her, and oh my
god, she gave me a lot of
headaches, but she grew into it
and became a
great
diamond dealer and had
$20 million accounts
, so really big
clients.  And once, once, once in
the week I uh uh
slept in New York to
open the safe, and only three people
knew the
code.  And then I taught people in my
hotel, so in my hotel room,
and um, I
sat on the table.  The students were
sitting on the bed and, um, she
then asked, "Can I
come by sometime when you're teaching?"
and she came and she thought it was
really great and learned
and learned and then she became
a non-professional
and she and I
founded ACI together.   That
was 30
[music]
years ago.  Then she came to Diamond
Mountain and did a three-year
retreat and
helped to build this temple here with her
own hands,
together with
others.  And I have never in my
life seen anyone who has
changed so much.  She was such a
difficult person.
And then she became this incredibly
happy person,
and then we had the
opportunity to do a second three-year
retreat, and I think she was
the only one who did a
six-
year retreat,
and people didn't know that
she had cancer the whole time.  She
already had cancer when I met her
.  And we didn't tell anyone
.  Nobody knew
that. And it just kept going
.   He
died some time ago, and people keep doing
these
prostrations.  But I think if
you really
want to prostrate yourself before your lamas, then grab
a shovel and build a temple.
So, something like that to help.  It's
really nice of the people who give me
a red envelope
.  But if I hand them a shovel
, they
might say: "No, I'm
not doing that."  And when you prostrate yourself,
when you bow before your
lineage, then perhaps think
of this kind.
This kind of
remembrance, it was such hard work for 20
years
to
build this place here with Mountain.  I asked my wife whether
the young
people should continue building it now
.  said, yes, let them
try it, because it makes them
strong, but if you want to honor the lamas
, then make a
monastery or something like that
.  This is a humiliation, not
this
ceremonial hard work.
Keep going for a little while longer, and uh,
afterwards there will be a Q&A
session.  So I'll do for another 15 minutes or so,
and then you can ask questions,
and you should definitely have questions about
how to continue
with your Diamond Way.   There is
a very unusual part in Gibson's book
, because it says that if you
study Lam Lamrim,
you will get eyes.   There is
a famous stupa in Nepal
.  Some people say that this is the
place where Lord Buddha
was born, but she is really famous because
she has these funny eyes
, these
Buddha eyes.
And Dr.  said, "But those are
small ones."
So, I explained that the reason for this is that the
marble slabs and the Borbodur stone
are about five stories high,
but we also have to take some consideration here so that
they fit into the landscape.  We do
n't want to disturb the mountain, and the
stubs should be elegant.
But eyes are very important, and someone told
Z Kappa that if
you
learn Lamrim, you will get the
eyes to
see the world.  And he got upset
and said, no, that's
not what it says in the
book.  And he said,
"Slam, those aren't the eyes. If
you study that, then you get the
eyes, but if you
do Lamrim, then you have these eyes to
see messages. And
by the way, Diamantwick, the author Johnny
Lam, and there was also this story
about Zum Kappa and Zum Papa's eyes, and
I checked that in the John Brady
database, and it's
actually on the last page of the
Lam
Channel. It's about the eyes.
[Music]
Lamrim, those are the
eyes. If you have Lamrim, then you have
the eyes, and if you don't, then you don't
. What does that mean for
us? There's a very, very
famous quote from Lord Buddha.
Someone asked him, 'Which
meditation posture is the best
?' And for 2000
years there's been this argument: 'Do you put your
left hand down first and then
place your right hand on top,
or bend your right leg first, or your
left leg first?' A big
argument,
and then someone asked him, 'What
is your
favorite posture?' And Lord Buddha
said, 'I have three.'  And they
said, which ones? He
said, I meditate when I lie in bed
, I meditate when I sit in a chair,
and I meditate when I
stand up. That's
all. And that's why I have a
suggestion for
you.
Classically speaking,
Lord Buddha said there are
three ways: lying down,
sitting, and standing. That means
practically, practically all the
time.
So, I suggest that until
we meet again in Mexico
City, whether we meet online
or in
person,
we try to meditate when we travel, when we go
somewhere by car or on
foot
, when you walk down the street
, for example, in
Shinen, or fly somewhere.
So every time you go
somewhere
, by car, however,
let's make a deal
. We're a
small
diamond group now,
together with the people
online until the 18th in Mexico
City, and then we'll make a deal that in
the
meantime, you keep an eye out for
messages. When you
sleep,  You might not have to
do this, but let's agree
that we'll do this especially
when we're traveling by car,
through the city,
or by
plane. Who agrees? There were
three people here, I think. But is that
cool? So, that's the
homework. Maybe someone will ask you
, what's your Diamond Way? What
's your Diamond Way homework? H,
well, when I'm traveling,
I have to see if I can
discover any messages. I always find tons.
I get lots and lots of messages on the
plane. I remember one woman who
kept looking at her phone. I do
n't know how many hours the flight to
Japan is. Eleven hours or
so, and she was on
her
phone for at least ten of them, and I looked at her sideways
, slightly
annoyed. Is this someone who's on their
phone all the time
? And then I wondered,
my God, what is she looking at for eleven
hours?
And, uh, when you go to the bathroom, you
look  Yeah, sometimes a
little more closely, what people are up to
. And I just wanted to see
which website she was on.
And then I
saw that you can turn the camera around
and then you can
see yourself. And she spent 11 hours
checking her makeup. I thought,
wow. And then I thought, oh, I
'm so much better. I didn't even know
you could do that with the
camera.
It makes me a much
better
person. Then I thought,
oh, that's a message.
She is the message. Maybe
she's showing me that I actually spend
11 hours thinking about myself,
that I'm thinking about this
. And maybe she hopes that
if I finally, finally understand this,
she
can finally sleep, and then
she's probably this Watini or
an angel, and all the time
she's trying to make sure I get this message.
But anyway,
as a group, as a
team, every time you're out and about,
look for the messages. A
message, if a scorpion
is climbing up your leg, that sort of thing.
That's  Truly one of the
greatest tactics in the Mantra is to
search for
messages. Was this woman,
for example, a Buddha? I can't
say that I know she
was a Buddha, but I also can't
say that she wasn't. And this
doubt
between
knowing she
wasn't or knowing she was, but
this doubt, is
very powerful karma. If you
want financial freedom and
want to hand out $100 bills all day long, or want to have the most amazing woman or
man, this is
the karma that
brings that about. Everything you've ever
dreamed of will come to you
. This
doubt
is incredibly powerful karma and
will
bring about strange, amazing things,
and that is very worthwhile.
It costs nothing to be a little paranoid
about this woman. It cost me 10 seconds
on the way to the toilet. We
also had a very
strange flight on the way back from
China.
Someone had diarrhea and had to throw up
, but that was a different
flight.
Anyway.  Have
you done your homework now?
And Angel, the angel and the devil, the
debate, we'll definitely
finish that sometime. Now
we'll do
questions and I have to
stop on time. Thank you very much.
What is the
message when we sit here
and see a scorpion? I believe
messages
are
tailor-made, and I believe that part of
this practice
is that I don't say what the
message is, but you have to
know that. I don't know what's going on in your
life right now. I don't know
what's happening in the lives of any of my
students
. And one thing about
the
messages is that they are created by the
miracles to
fit you perfectly. And
two people
can receive a
different message from the same incident, for example, from this scorpion that was just here.
And that's the cool thing
about messages. And one thing about the
Diamond Way is that it's all a
personal message from Buddha, and you
can take it and
use it. That's the Diamond Way.
You have me  I was asked to
teach it now, and I'm teaching it.
Okay. To the people in Malaysia,
congratulations on your new
[music]
Stuper.
I don't yet have any
English,
Chinese, or English.
Channel的,因為我根本不是不是佛不是可以如何去應用這些金 剛稱的教授來去幫助我現在提高或者說我怎麼去理解這些金剛的內容
Ah, okay, now comes the translation.
So, thank you for the teachings over
the last two
days.  It's a lot about
visualization, for example that we
see ourselves as Manjusri, but I can't do that.  I have
trouble seeing myself as a Manjusri
.  What can we
do if these this visualization,
if we have problems with the
visualizations?  What  What can I
do to bring these
Diamond Way teachings into my life
?
One thing John Brady has done with his
database is to
add 300,000 books,
and it will probably take him another 300
years to finish. He has to
stay here until then. It's just
incredible. The Western
classics, on which Western
universities are based, there are
maybe 500 books in a
classical library, and in
Asia there are 300,000.
They are all of very
high quality.
But
these are all extraordinary
books, and each one can lead to
enlightenment
. Yesterday we were talking about Sutras and
Chastras. There are
900,
Sutras and 700,000
Chastras and
200,000
commentaries,
and
people used to divide all these
books into 12 categories in the
Kangier.
So the entire Kangier has only
12 sections
or
divisions. John Brady's database
has approximately  1000
different
areas and it's correctly
categorized.
And why am I mentioning this? Why am I talking about
it? There are
160 tantras in the database.
Yogini is one, Manjushri is one, Amitaba
is
one, but John
Brady's system has
identified 160, and
each of them, for example,
Yogini,
has
subcategories like how to meditate,
how to die, how to
perform the initiation ceremony, and so
on. And I asked my teacher
, I said, you teach us three
or four tantric traditions. We
mainly get, so basically
two, Diamantika and Reugini,
but there are
160, and all my
friends who studied with other teachers
get 10, 20, 50, and I
said, we only have two.
He said that's all we
practice in the tantric monastery there.
So, there are thousands of
monasteries, but there are only two
tantric monasteries, and he said,
We only learn these two. And I
said, wow,
why are there all the
others then? He said, everyone is
different.
Everyone needs a
different teaching, and that's why there are five
different houses, because
everyone needs something
different, just like my
wife tried on 42 different pairs of jeans
. I was annoyed and had to
stand and wait, and I was a bit annoyed the whole time,
and she didn't
buy a single pair of those jeans. And in Tantra, there are 160
different pairs of jeans, 160 different
sacred
beings, and maybe even 1000, but
anyway, there are 160 in the database.
You
came to this one, but if the question is, "
I really have no connection to
Jamantika
[music]
terrifying, and I find that kind of
terrifying too,"
then there's anything else
to
choose from, and my teacher
said, "Well, I think you're more of
a Batriogini
type," so in my teacher's tradition,
which is 2000 years old
, there are different
choices. You can
take the tough type, or
The wonderful angel. I personally
prefer the wonderful angel.
So, if you're on the Diamond Way,
then you should
have a few options,
different choices,
like
Diamantika or
Treogini, but you don't have to
decide right now. These options are there
, and if it doesn't
feel like it's the right fit right away, do
n't worry about it.
You'll
change, or you'll get a different
tradition. It
's always Lord Buddha, who
just looks like 42 different pairs of
jeans or 160
different ones. But I
also think if you feel more drawn to a
female Buddha in
Treogini, that's
okay. And some
need an
authoritarian
president, whose name I won't mention here
. It always depends.
What's cool about Diamantwick is that there are
many choices, and
if it doesn't
fit right away, then choose the one that fits better
.
But another
possibility
is that in Geschekos, there are
five
different
themes:
Logic, Mind Only,
Middle Way,
Logic, and so on. And when I
Personally, for example, when we got to logic
, I hated it and I
said, no, this isn't for me. I'm
quitting, I'm giving up
. I'm just
not interested in it at all. It's all nonsense.
I had real problems with it,
and my teacher back then couldn't speak
English, and he spoke in Bethian,
and I said I didn't
understand a word. Then he
tried to explain logic in
broken English,
and I've told this story many times
. I was walking back from his room to
mine, and he
had just given me a lesson in
logic. I was
sleeping on the cement floor of a garage
in a sleeping bag because I had no money,
along with a drunk who
was also sleeping there, and I was always
afraid he would kill me one night
.
Anyway, I was standing under a
tree, thinking, oh man, I
really don't know if I
can go through with this.
And then this voice came to
me and said, you, you will
Now. This is important. This is something
you have to do. Now pull yourself
together. And then I thought,
wow, so this is a
message. And in that moment I
thought, okay, so I'm going to do this
now.
This is the one
thing I dislike the most.
And I received the message
that I should do what
I dislike the most, because that's
the practice you don't yet have and that you
need, the one you dislike is the one you're
still
missing inside. And I thought, h, that's
kind of an interesting
idea,
and John Brady, Connie, can you
give me other choices?
So, you can just wait until
something comes along that really
suits you. But the other option is
maybe that what
you're not so drawn to
, that might be what
you need. And then I
became really good at logic. I'm the best,
and I practically killed myself trying to figure that out,
and now I can, and that
's the most
important thing, the most valuable thing. So don't think  It's not always about what
feels comfortable,
but maybe it's what
you don't
feel drawn to.
So sometimes in Buddhism, you should
maybe do what you don't feel drawn to
, because otherwise you won't learn
anything new. Don't forget that.
Yesterday I was
reading in Jon Kappa's book, and at that
moment a hummingbird appeared.
So Ki said that this is an indication,
that it's a sign
for some, a kind of easy path to
enlightenment.
So that was a very good sign, a
good
omen, if I... But what should
you do if you see bad signs
? So yes,
see bad signs. A lama once said something about that.
I'm trying to remember.
I was talking to my
lama. He was his toilet cleaner, his
lawn,
and it
's
a difficult, dirty job,
but you always hear everything
they say to others.
And someone
said,
Rimpe, sometimes I have these
wonderful signs in dreams, and I
see that I... the sky  It opens and
a body descends from the sky,
and they are incredible
dreams. So my first question is, how do
I interpret
this? And
then sometimes I have nightmares and I
see terrible things in the
dream, like bad omens,
but I don't know how to
interpret them.
And his answer in the
Diamond Way was, if you have a wonderful
trauma and something amazing happens
and you fly or you meet a
Buddha, that's
a sign that you're making progress.
If you see a hummingbird, and you
feel that it's a guide on the
path to enlightenment, that's a
good
sign.
And he said, "
Congratulations."  I thought it was weird to
congratulate someone on a dream,
but he said it. And then
the person said, "Yeah, and what about the
nightmares?" And then he said, "Then
you probably
ate something wrong in the afternoon. Too much pizza or something
. A rotten egg or
something. So he just said, [ __ ],
whatever.
If it's like
that, if a cloud is blocking the sun
, then he said, do
n't pay too much
attention to it with nightmares.
Maybe you ate something wrong
. Like when you
need to fart. You can just ignore that.
So, think about those good
messages, those good visions,
and with the bad
things, just say, go
away, don't even give it a second thought, don't even
think about it,
if there's a scorpion
running around, then so what?
[Music] is
singing in Spanish.
There's an
online age. Hello
Grandfather. You said you
normally have to complete the Dexterity course before
Diamond
B.
What seeds do we have?
How can we  Should we reinvest in
this seed so it continues?
My opinion is, if you
've completed the 18 courses and you do the 18
Diamond Way courses, then
your practice is more
solid,
and there's a huge shortage of teachers for these things
we're discussing here.
It's like if there were only two doctors in New York or
Singapore
. There are only a few people
for thousands of people who
can teach this. So all these
people are suffering, and there's a
shortage of
hearts, and that's why I think we have to do
what we
can to train more doctors. But of
course, after just
two weeks of training, they don't just hand you a scalpel
and let you
perform heart surgery. But we don't have much
time left. You don't know how much time you
have. I don't know how long I have left to
live. We have to
take care of this now. There
are
prerequisites, and it's better if
you can do the
18 courses in ACI and the Diamond Way
courses.
There are
these
general practitioners. I have such a
great doctor...  Doctors as old as
me, and uh, they don't make them anymore
.
Nowadays, if you
go to the doctor with a headache,
you say, "Oh yes, yes, yes, you need to see a
headache specialist,
and if you say
I'm also having problems with my brain, then they send
you to another specialist." And
it's
very rare to find
general practitioners
who are familiar with all these different problems
. I would
like to train general practitioners, and
I think
it would be good if you covered many
topics so you
could address a wide range of issues. And then, if
someone asks you about bad
or good signs, you'll have the
answer.
The best doctors I know
never stop
learning. If you're allowed to, I can
come by next week, and they'll
say, "No, I'm at
a continuing education course." Yes, but you're
already 60 or 70 years old. But they say,
no, I absolutely want to do this continuing education course
and learn about even more new
technologies and new things. My
wife, for example,
had a knee replacement,
and this doctor  The
operation is performed with a
robot. There are
many who do it manually, but
the robot is much more precise
and faster.
These days, you can't even
tell which
knee was operated on,
and such a
person is already incredibly skilled and
knowledgeable, but
they have continued their
education in
this robotic technique.
So, personally, I prefer to
go to a surgeon who
knows both techniques.
And as a
teacher, I don't want you coming to me
asking whether you should take 14 or 15 courses
.
I can probably
teach annoying questions after I've
done 13.
So, learn robotic technology
and also learn the
skill of traditional
surgery. If you hand
a child a scalpel
and
say, "You can operate with this," then
I would say, "No,
I'd rather wait
."
It's a difficult
decision.
If you wait 50 years until you
have enough experience, then you can only
help a few people, but you want to...  Don't rush it either
. I stand by
what Tim
says, but you should never stop
learning. You can
learn the Diamond Way hundreds of times in a lifetime and still
not master it.
But as quickly as you
can, try to learn as much as
you can to help the
most people
. And if you
want to know the details, ask
Tim
and
Maria. They teach, and yeah, so
just try.